Guide to the Charlie Cobb Interviews, 2012-2013 RL.11333
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- This Nonviolent Stuff Will Get You Killed Interviews, 2012-2013; 3
  - Watkins, Hollis, 2012-07-18; 65
    - Hollis Watkins June 4 2012.mp3, 0:48:07 (Server TTS, E-folder RL11333-LFF-0003)
      In person in Clinton, TN at the children's defense fund. Discusses Hollis reaction to the name Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee, name startled him. First heard of SNCC when he got to McComb, he believes he heard it in Bob Moses office. Hollis thoughts on nonviolence and violence, was reluctant about nonviolence. Nonviolence was just talked about in the workshops. Discussed Vernon Dahmer who also wasn't nonviolent. Discussed Crazy Negro terminology, and Man Porter, a local "crazy negro", Hollis says the crazy negro terminology was a way of explaining why they would leave black man who spoke their mind and stood up for themselves, Ex: why would you beat up a crazy man?. Also discussed when he took a shift guarding the home with a gun from a couple who was allowing him to stay at their home.
    - part 1 Hollis and cobb3.mp3, 0:28:41 (Server TTS, E-folder RL11333-LFF-0003)
      Transcript available. Hollis and Cobb, (poor quality).
    - part 2 hollis and cobb2.mp3, 0:54:00 (Server TTS, E-folder RL11333-LFF-0003)
    - Transcript_WatkinsHollis_CobbTNVSGYK.docx (Server TTS, E-folder RL11333-LFF-0003)